Guide to the Catholic Apostolic Church Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Catholic Apostolic Church Records
1825-1973
RG 55
Yale University Divinity School Library
3
(10 boxes)
The papers consist primarily of printed pamphlets and sermons. The Catholic Apostolic Church was an eschatologically oriented group which split from the Church of England in the early 19th century.
Catholic Apostolic Church
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The Catholic Apostolic Church originated in England during the early 1830's, developing out of a revivalist group led by Henry Drummond. The members of the CAC have been widely designated as Irvingites, despite their disclaimers of the centrality of Edward Irving in the formation and development of the church. Irving was a member of Drummond's group and an influential preacher in London who was accused of heresy and expelled from the ministry of the Church of Scotland in 1833. Various aspects of the theology and terminology of the CAC have been traced to the teachings of Irving, but he was never accorded a high position in the hierarchy of the church and died only two years after the formal establishment of the CAC.
Theologically, CAC has been characterized by the strong eschatological expectation, belief in Irving's view of Christ assumption of sinful human flesh, and an extremely literalistic method of Biblical interpretation. In preparation for the imminent Second Advent of Christ, the group gathered around Drummond felt called to reinstate the full complement of ministries of the primitive church, and later to add other positions of ministry resulting in a hierarchical structure that included apostles, prophets, evangelists, pastors, teachers, seraphim, angels, deacons and coadjutors.
The first 'apostle', John Bate Cardale, was appointed in 1832 and was joined by eleven other 'apostles' before the first Council of Zion was held in 1835. One of the first actions of the Council of Zion was the sending of the statements, or testimonies, to the bishops of the Church of England and King William IV, which set forth the mission of the Church. The 'apostles' then began missionary work on the continent and in South America, each 'apostle' being assigned a country or countries for his special attention. The work met with particular success in Holland, Germany, and Prussia, attracting many people of social and political prominence.
From the first, the CAC was distinctive in its polity and practices. In England, the church centered around the seven churches in London ( modeled after those in the book of Revelation), chief of which was the church in Gordon Square, built in 1853. The Church was supervised as a whole from the Apostles' Chapel at Albury. An increasing inclination toward the Catholic doctrine and practices was apparent as the church developed, due in part to the influence of the ideas encountered in its missionary work and the views of the Tractarian movement in England. This trend was reflected in an elevated understanding of the sacraments and a preference for a more elaborate liturgy.
The church passed through a severe crisis in 1901 when the last of the 'apostles' died. Because the 'apostles' had been expected to survive until the second coming, no provision had been made for their replacement. Church officials of lesser rank therefore assumed leadership of the church, and its activities continued on a reduced scale. As more and more officials passed away and no 'apostles' were available to appoint new leaders, local congregations ceased to meet and church buildings were sold, beginning in the late 1940's. Many church members were reabsorbed into the Church of England, although there is evidence that Catholic Apostolic Church members in many countries have retained a special identity and maintain communication with each other, despite the formal disbanding of the group.
For further information regarding the Catholic Apostolic Church see The History and Doctrine of Irvingism by Edward Miller (1878), The Catholic Apostolic Church by P.E. Shaw (1946), and A History of Creeds and Confessional of Faith by William A Curtis (1911).
Scope and Contents
This collection of pamphlet material supplements the Library's cataloged collection of books related to the Catholic Apostolic Church. The pamphlets and books were acquired in 1973 from the Bodleian Library in Oxford and presumably represent duplicates in the collection which came to the Bodleian from Norman Priddle, librarian of the Catholic Apostolic Church.
The pamphlets and ephemeral material of Record Group 55 offer to researchers an opportunity to examine the life of the Catholic Church in a way which would not have been possible during its active years, due to the desire of the Church to hold its more intricate beliefs and political struggles secret from the world at large. Biographical information about the important figures in the Catholic Apostolic Church is provided by the collection as well as bibliographic information regarding their writings.
It is difficult to determine how accurate a portrait of the Catholic Apostolic Church is provided by this collection. Although most of the 'apostles' are represented, the degree of representation varies. No doubt the collection documents theological issues and historical controversies with corresponding inconsistency. The collection does, however, provide valuable insight into the Church's interest in prophecy, including specific predictions about the Eschaton, in Biblical number symbolism and in elaborate symbolism in liturgical practice.
One historian has characterized the liturgical emphasis of the Catholic Apostolic as follows; "Its quickly developed passion for gorgeous ceremonial and vestments, and its liturgical enthusiasm reflect the antiquarian and sensuous tastes of an age which studied as well as made history, which was devoted, however crudely, to art, and form, and color, and which gave birth to the Oxford Movement." (William A. Curtis, A History of Creeds and Confessions of Faith. Edinburgh; T and T Clark, 1911, p.378.) The theoretical writings and liturgical tools available in this collection provide a basis for fresh evaluation of the Catholic Apostolic Church's development of liturgy.
Series I, Sermons and Treatises, contains works on various subjects, arranged alphabetically by author. The titles and dates of these works are provided as available. Anonymous writings appear at the end of the series and are arranged chronologically. These anonymous documents are followed by one folder of pamphlets which were received with the collection but which could appear to have no direct relation to the Catholic Apostolic Church. It is possible that such pamphlets remain in the alphabetical section.
Series II, Historical Lists and Descriptions, includes A. Annals, B. Bibliographic information, C. Biographical Information, and D. Information regarding church buildings. The materials in this series provide concise documentation of the history of the church and its more prominent members.
Series II, Tools for worship and Instruction, includes A. Charts and lectionaries, B. Orders of worship, C. Materials related to doctrinal instruction and polity.
Arrangement
I. Sermons and treatises, 1825-1971, n.d.
II. Historical list and Description, 1826-1973, n.d.
III. Tools for worship and Instruction, 1885-1973, n.d.
Eschatology; Religious thought -- 19th century; Second Advent; Sects; Sermons, English; Pamphlets; Sermons; Clergy; Armstrong, Nicholas, 1801-1879; Cardale, John Bate, 1802-1877; Drummond, Henry, 1786-1860; Heath, Edward, 1845-1929; Irving, Edward, 1792-1834; Catholic Apostolic Church
- Sermons and Treatises, 1825-1971, n.d.; Series I
  - Ackery, John Williams (1828-1908)
    - Paper on the Anointing of the Sick, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Address delivered by the Angel of the Church in Southwark, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albrecht, Ludwig (1861-1931)
    - Address by Pastor Albrecht, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The 68th Psalm: A Biblical Study, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Homily, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Faith, Hope and Love, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The way to the Heavenly Inheritance, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The work by apostles at the end of the dispensation, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson William
    - The Glasgow Painting Medium, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, William ( -1971)
    - Truths for our days, Which Every Christian Should Know and Believe, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andrew, John
    - The Parables of the Kingdom, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andrews, Williams Watson (1810-1897)
    - The Catholic Apostolic Church: Its History..., 1866 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Present and abiding Humanity of our Lord, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Teaching: A Review of God's mode of working among His People by Twelve and Seventy, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Armstrong, Nicholas (1801-1879)
    - The Church as it ought to be; A Sermon, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Funeral Sermon, delivered over the grave of the Late Rev. Washington Wilks, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Psalm and the Reading of the Scriptures, with Exposition and the Sermon: being the Services at the opening of the Salem Chapel, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Exposition and Sermon, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Corinthian and Galatian Sins against the Spirt of Christ, and A Review of the Epistle to the Hebrews: Two Sermons, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Restoration of Apostles, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ashford, Edward James ( -1920)
    - Homilies and Sermons, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barclay, Archibald Campbell (1804-1860)
    - The Four Dispensations, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barker, Joseph (1806-1875)
    - The Popular Imperfections of the Bible, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bayford, Augustus Frederic (1809-1874)
    - Prove All Things: Hold Fast That Which is Good, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bell, Thomas George
    - To The Rev. S.S Wood, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blunt, R. H.
    - The Significance of Numbers in the Bible, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Boase, C.W.
    - see Caird, Williams Renny
  - Bohm, Charles John Thomas (1812-1880)
    - Baptism of Infants, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Holy Baptism, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Holy Catholic Church, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Lord's Supper, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - On the Decline of the Church, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Second Coming Of Christ and His Kingdom in Visible Glory, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - What is the Duty of Christians in the Present Times?, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bramley, Edwin (1879-1955)
    - The Signification of Numbers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bramley-Moore, William Joseph (1831-1918)
    - On The Number 40, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brown, James
    - A Brief History of Type-printing in Connection with the Circulation of the Bible, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bulteel, H. R.
    - The Reigns of David and Solomon, Typical of the State Church under the First and Second Advent of Christ: A Sermon, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burne, Newdigate Hooper K. 1830-1898
    - Letter Addressed to Members of the Congress at Albury, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Caird, William Renny ?(1823-1894)
    - An Address on the instant Coming of the Lord, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - To the Elders and Deacon Serving... the Church of Scotland (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Capadose, Abraham
    - Sermon on Habakkuk III, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Capadose, Isaac (1834-1920) (see also: Ashford E.: Heath, E.)
    - Homily on Prayer, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Remarks made by the Coadjutor at a Conference on the Question of Sunday Trading, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - On the Office of Angel in the Church of Christ, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Church in Relation to the World, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sermon: According to your Faith, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Two Sermons, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - A Sermon: Ephraim and Benjamin and Manasseh, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sermon, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - A Sermon Preached in the Apostles Chapel at Albury, on the feast of all Angels, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ministries Delivered at Albury on Easter Sunday, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - A Sermon Preached in the Apostles Chapel at Albury: Shut thy Doors, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury: That Which Was Lost, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Feast of Shophar, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily: The Net, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Sharp Knives, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sermon: Joseph the Dreamer, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Laver: Sermon Delivered at the Apostles Chapel at Albury, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily Delivered in the Apostles Chapel at Albury, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Homily, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sermon Delivered at Albury, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Pastoral Teaching: The Lord's Day, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Looking for the Blessed Hope, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Meditation on the Work of Redemption, n.d (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cardale, John Bate (1802-1877)
    - On the Extraordinary manifestation in Port Glasgow, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Teachings Addresses to Candidate for the laying On of Apostles' Hands, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Man, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - A Discourse Delivered in the Catholic Apostolic Church, Gordon Square, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Structure of the Apocalypse, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - A Word of Ministry on the day of the Commemoration of all Saints, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Notes of Lectures Delivered in the Seven Churches in London, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carlyle, Thomas (1803-1892)
    - On our Present Position in Spiritual Chronology, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Pleadings With my Mother: The Church in Scotland, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Shooting Niagara: And After?, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cooper, Thomas (1805-1892)
    - To the Young Men of the Working Classes, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Copinger, Walter Arthur (1880-1951)
    - A Testimony of Antiquity, Being a Reprint of the Homily of Elfric, Archbishop of Canterbury (Copinger, editor), 1877 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - A Premonitory Cry; Or, A Note of Warning and Testimony of Hope, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cuming, Robert Strickland ( -1917)
    - Sermon: The Handwriting Over Against the Candlestick, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dalton, Henry (1805-1867)
    - Body, Soul, and Spirit: A Sermon, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Our Two Dangers, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - An Address Delivered to the Prophets assembled at Albury, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - The Office of Bishop under Apostles, and the Office of Bishop without Apostles, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Daniel, Ivor ( 1929)
    - Sermon, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Davenport, John Sidney (1809-1900)
    - The Parousia, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Davson, Wilfred Maynard (1875-1971)
    - 1850-1950 in the Lord's Work, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Confirmation and Admission to Regular Communion, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Davy John T
    - A Teaching on Our Present Position, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dougharty, Walter
    - The Last Days, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Dow, William (1800-1855)
    - Midnight Musings, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Ten Homilies (reprint), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Dowglass, Thomas ( -1857)
    - Job, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Drummond, Henry (1786-1860)
    - On the Seed of Isaac, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - A Christian View of the State of the Country, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Church of Christ, AD. 1834 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Narrative of the Circumstances which led to the setting Up of the Church of Christ at Albury, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - On the numbers in Daniel, 1835 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Postscript to the 'The Abstract Principles of Revealed Religion', 1846 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Remarks on Dr Wiseman's Sermon on the Gorham Case, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - A Plea for the Rights and Liberties of Women, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - A Brief Account of the Commencement of the Lord's work to restore His Church, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Speech in the House of Commons on the Second Reading of the Ecclesiastical Titles Bill, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Fate of Christendom, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - On the Future Destinies of the Celestial Bodies, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Tracts for the Church in 1856 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Stone Cut out of the Mountation, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Remarks on the Ministry of Instruction in the Church, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letter to Mr Bright on his plan for turning the English Monarchy into Democracy, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letter to the Working Classes..., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Drysdale, James
    - Christ's Second Advent in Daniel (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dunworth, James ( 1946)
    - Sermon: The Lord's Day, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Easton, James Marshall (1867-1944)
    - Sermon: The Hope of Translation, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ministry on the Book of the Psalms, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Edgcombe, Alberta L.F.
    - For Little Children: Four Tracts, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Entwisle, Alfred
    - Cremation or Burial: How Should We Dispose of Our Dead?, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fink-Jensen, J
    - From Saul to Paul: A Biblical Study Of the Earliest Days of the Church, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fowkes, Thomas
    - Sectarianism, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Francis, John George ( -1889)
    - Outlines of the Ministry, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Catholicism, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Friebe, Alwin Ottamar Theodor (1848-1926)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Homily, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Gandy, Henry
    - The Church Present and Future (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Coming of Christ and his Kingdom (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Happy Company, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Gloomy City, n.d (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Time of our visitation, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Gate of the Upland Way: The Creed (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gosse, Phillip Henry, n.d.
    - The Revelation: How is it to be Interpreted?, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gould, Victor Royd
    - Sermon: Evolution, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Sermon, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Graham, Joseph (1864-1942)
    - Sermon, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The Work Fulfilled by Apostles in Our Day Teaching, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Teaching, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Sermon: The Covering of the Tabernacle, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Groser, Thomas
    - The Charter of the Kingdom: A Sermon, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Haigh, Alfred
    - The Presence of the Holy Ghost as Symbolized by fire: Sermon, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hall, Sophy
    - The Two Thomas Carlyles, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hammond, Charles (1840-1922)
    - Psalm XXVII, 4-5: Sermon, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hamp, W.B.
    - The Congregation in Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Harris T.L.
    - The Redeemed Body, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Heath, Charles Edward Lewis (1869-1946)
    - Lecture to the Young Men of the Central Church on the Evolution of the Apostles Liturgy, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Sermon Delivered to the Congregation in Albury, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Sermon: Separation of the Apostles, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Song Of Solomon, n.d (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Heath, Christopher Barclay
    - Outline of the Life Of Christ, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - The Development of the Liturgy and the Origins of its Prayer, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Heath, Edward (1845-1929) (see also: Ashford, E)
    - Homily, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - A Sermon Preached at Albury, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Paper on the Gift of Prophecy and the Duty of Angels with Regard to Prophetic Persons, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Resurrection: A Sermon, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - The Transition to a New Dispensation: A Sermon, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - The Sin Offering: A Sermon, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - A Homily Delivered at Albury, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - A Sermon Preached at Albury, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Paper on the danger of Regarding as Definite Dogmatic Statements Things Concerning the Coming of the Lord, Which God has revealed in Part..., 1902 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Letter to the angel Evangelists...(with I. Capadose, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Sermon Preached in the Apostles Chapel at Albury, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Preached at Albury, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Corres. Concerning Arrangements for the Omission of the Assembly of the seven Churches...(with I Capadose), 1906 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Confidential Letter on Sexual Matters, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Preached at Albury, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homilies Delivered at Albury (Feb 2, Oct 18), 1908 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Sermon Preached in the Apostles, Chapel at Albury, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered in the Apostles' Chapel at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered in the Apostles Chapel at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered in the Apostles' Chapel at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Sermon Delivered at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Suffrage for Women: No Parallel in Recommendation for Sevenfold Deaconship, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Sermon, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - The Kingdom of Christ: A Sermon Preached at Albury, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Preached at Albury, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Remarks on the Question Whether and To What Extent. It is Desirable that Members of the Congregations Gathered Under the Apostles Should Bequeath..., 1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Archbishop Proposal that a Pastoral Letter be read in all the Churches on Sunday, 6th June, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Note on Conversion, With Reference to the Letters of Messrs. A and B., and Letter, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Priesthood and Kingship of Christ, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Two Homilies Delivered at Albury, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Sermon, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - A Reign of Christ: A Sermon Preached at Albury, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily Delivered at Albury, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homily, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 29)